[Music]
hi to all of you this is a webinar being
organized by clear tax and I say say
Lombard in terms of how do you handle
the SME risk during COBIT times just to
give you a brief myself ian Tremonti I
head the SME business and I say al-ahmad
and just to tell a brief about our
company I say say Lombard the first is
basically it is a largest private sector
insurance company and we are a focused
company in terms of SMEs in terms across
the country and we are a technology
driven company in terms of solving the
issues of SMEs using technology and from
the insurance point of view just to give
you something in terms of some of the
awards we have received I mean in a
brief it is tnb awards are done in racks
loads of innovative awards that IPI outs
the brief are all that is I say say
Lombard is a channel friendly company is
a customer friendly company is a
technology company and innovative
company fast in a broad thought process
about I say Salem but this is a brief
about that I don't think I should talk
more about that let me come to in terms
of topic
how are the SME is getting affected at
this one of time because of of it and
what are the challenges they're facing
and from the insurance point of view
what are the things they need to be
aware of it so that should be the
thought process around the next 40
minutes in terms of discussing with each
one of you so this is the first slide in
terms of first cut view in terms of
impact of Ovid on the SME is the
startups and interference ESCO bid has
hit them and majority areas but two
three areas where it has strongly hit
them the first is a cash flow I mean one
of the biggest thing required for SMEs
or MSME is the starter of the
entrepreneurs is there is has to a
continuity of cash flow that continuity
has got disturbed because of the
scoville the second thing that has hit
them hard is basically the supply chain
mr.
disruptions and in terms of supply chain
to substance what has happened is it is
both in the demand side as well as in
supply side if you see this SMEs are
being supplied by some of the micros
amines or the small startups and they
supply to the large companies and retail
company things both the side has got
disturbed m in terms that is lesser
demand out there and the supply to this
companies also has got disturbed and it
is not only that this supply chain
disruption is also happened because
there is a log jam at in terms of
exporting put happening across the
countries it is not only domestic it is
both at the exporting port as well the
third of course we just hit them very
hard is the labor force and in terms of
labor force so there is a huge
migratory population so we which has
been working with SMEs and estimates
across the country in major cities like
Delhi Bombay Chennai Bangalore all those
major since Pune and this labor has
sifted bagged majority of shifted back
to the hometown and there is a circus of
labor out there so there it is no more a
one problem in terms of of it or it is
actually a multiple problem being
surrounding the SMEs at this point of
time so there are challenges on price
variations there are production shut
down their export issues so these are
broad areas in terms of how the SMEs are
getting affected this one of time from
the Cobell point of view this is a broad
slide in terms of what is the impact of
lockdown on the risks the way we see
SMEs are it is not a risk in terms of
from insurance ponder we define it as a
risk how do you see the risks of SMEs in
the cogut time there are multiple
parameters will be saying how the risk
is there whether the plant is sent down
running but the process is continuous or
batch process whether there is
discontinuity in the raw material supply
but I mean what is the percentage of the
stocks in your business model so these
are multiple areas on basis of which the
risk parameters change it from this
point of view but if you see I am
putting agreed in terms of which are the
areas of which are the companies which
are born affected the most because of
the covert of the chemical the textile
and the plastic and the problem the
store the storage and I mean if you see
the low or the medium on the
pharmaceuticals the power generations
low basically food processing FMCG and
the very low basically are those non
industrial is like the schools colleges
are probably
subby sector industries or the pipelines
so these are lesser affected from the
risk point of view from ponte I mean
angle so these are the broad grid in
terms of where you are placed in each of
this angle just to put a thought around
that in terms of sectors what I've done
is we're putting line of businesses the
way we define insurance basically
whether it is a fire insurance whether
it's engineering insurance with the
marina cargo logistic insurance W C
stands for the workmen compensation
insurance and liability insurance and
the miscellaneous insurance so how has
the risk change in terms of for in each
of these product lines probably in the
fire the biggest risk changing would be
the stock accumulation or the business
interruption risks because the business
has got affected and is not adding to
across profit so there is a change of
risk out there and because the supply is
not there the stock is giving activity
that's the risk increase of risk are
there in engineering the the bigger the
risk is basically the unattended side I
mean all of a sudden you see the metros
you see the road constructions the
machines are lying on the road or the
equipment's are lying on the road the
Liberals are not there the security
guards are not there the risk all of a
sudden is open and it's open to burglary
theft damage all those things in terms
of marine cargo the major challenges
basically our supply chain disruptions I
mean lot of trucks salmon in the last
3-4 months they're under strangled on
the road I mean they're not supplied the
goods to the consumer because the
consumer itself on the trader although I
mean the receiver of the goods
themselves closes shop I mean nobody's
there to receive those goods in terms of
wco the Walkman compensations the
biggest challenges the labor has
relocated I mean today in a factory if
the 100 levels used to walk probably 30
are walking and that is a change of
Labour's working out there's some much
gone back to homes some new believers
have gone back so there is a labor
relocation problem that's happening in
terms of liability the biggest challenge
that has happened to me over to the
cyberattack I mean if you see a majority
of all of us are working from home today
I'm giving this webinar for my home so
when you are working from home a unlike
when you're walking from a company you
have walk when you're walking in a
company then you have a much secure
network of cyber in a home you use your
own Wi-Fi or home Wi-Fi to access your
databases informations or the company
sites on our things and there is
very high chance of cyberattacks of them
so we'll talk about all those things I
mean I will be talking detail about each
one of these parameters in the coming
slides and we'll see how what steps you
need to take in terms of safeguard
yourselves or what are the risk
guidelines or what are the insurance
guidelines of the regulatory guidelines
around that so that you are aware of the
steps and changes to take out so that's
we start with the property risks
basically there is a fire insurance and
the engineering insurance one of the
biggest questions which are always
facing the scientists for basically
solved this is I'm in a very simple
dumpster if your plant stops being
operational for 30 days it becomes a
silent dress and it has to rate it
differently and you have to intimate to
the insurance company so that your plant
has become silent other things and if
you are not implemented I mean the
regulation says that oh and in the
silent is a claims comes it does not get
covered what has happened is this is not
a individual induced silent risk this is
a gamma to induce aisle interest because
there is a log down across have come
because the government notifications so
what the regulator has done a regular
dismiss you know my idea that is an
integral development of India regulator
has done is they have given guidelines
that this continued EMA cover should be
considered as continuity even if there
is the exceed 30 days so there is no
challenge around that but if you have a
bigger risk please keep your client
insurance company posted about that I
mean there is a condom already the
rebuild has given those guidelines for
scene continuity it's not a normal
silent if there's lockdown induced but
oh my suggestions to each one of you
please just put in a mail to insurance
company saying there is a continuity of
non-operational clients or probably the
lockdown stun to me just in a safe aside
I mean even if the regulator is given
but on a surface I'd do that the
regulator is already given the
guidelines saying even if it is locked
or if it's non of course in 30 days the
continuity of power will be there it
will not become stress asylum prism the
second questions normally which comes is
does I mean your property policy covers
the loss of profit because lot of plants
have got covered I mean and that the
operation has got stopped and their loss
of there is a loss of profit and
basically your loss of profit covers in
terms of
had you been operational during this
period you're profitable of you now on
that and does the insurance policy
covers that so let me give what is
business interruption risk in loss of
profit cover is basically this is which
can cover a loss income or continuing
expenses well the business is closed
being repaired because of a disaster or
that is a in short barrel of a fire
policy acting on basis of which this
loss of apples so pandemic is not an in
short pants so loss of profit is not
covered in this fire policy or even in
your loss of profit policy so that's a
big mission over because people sake by
even if there's loss of profit please
pay for that that's not covered in this
policy that I thought I'll just share
with you I mean give a clarity around
this these are on the left side I put in
some questions and on the right side I
put in explanations out there the
questions is basically there is a shoe
around acuity saw the insurance company
or some of the clients or the customers
asked can we have option of extending
the policy on a pro-rata basis so the
order to take a shot critical of policy
because there is liquid two issues here
you can take a short field policy the
difference between a short period and a
pro-rata is in a pro-rata policy
whatever is the annual premium you've
divided proportionately for the time you
want to take that is peretta in a short
period you charge a little bit have in
the peretta so if you take a short term
policy a short period policy or a
smaller duration policy you have to pay
for a shorter period also the short
wheelbase is not at a pro-rata business
so for example if for a 30% of time you
might have to pay for a 40% of the
premium that's the way it is sorted so
you can always stop I mean take a short
period policy a small duration policy
that is issues around liquidity I've
already talked about in the pending we
cover it's not covered so what should we
focus basically post lockdown when the
situation gradually resumes to three
things one of course when the lockdown
is over the first thing is restarting is
not an easy process please follow all
guidelines for restarting because you
might be operating in a chemical plant
or a manufacturing plant or probably
ancillary units but there are you have
manuals for restarting each of the
plants of the factories
machines please follow that and what
would have happened is because a plant
is closed although the supply has not
been done for years your summon sure
would have changed all your stocks would
have got increased so you have to
redefine or something so the insurance
company there is it huge fluctuations
around do some ensure please intimate
our insurance company accordingly this
is and this also some I mean SME is they
put me mail somebody saying was if that
is the plan we start down why do I need
to take in for himself I mean this
expense item that means stop my
insurance and once the plant starts I
will do that I've just given two
examples below see I mean risk and he to
whether your operation lawyer proves
this don't differentiate between those
things so there are two big K I mean
plants one in Chandigarh one and said
tagless chemicals that isn't the hedge
and there's huge losses I mean even if
the plants are short they're huge losses
I can give an example even when I say
al-ahmad we had one came in the month
and there was a huge loss of around 20
24 crores of premium I mean the law
claims amount so the don't keep your
plant uninsured that's the thought
process even if that's a lockdown please
don't keep a plan uninsured because
risks can hit you even if they're closed
so this is one of the photographs I mean
since it's in a PDF I am NOT good so
though we lose out there but basically
even if claims has come we have actually
used drones to do inspections of those
risks come and you can see those four of
these photographs taken by drones from
the air and those drones are used to do
the survey because as a customer centric
company it is very critical that even if
there is log down you have to need to
stand behind a customer to help you at
the time of claim so we actually use
drones through the service and with the
basis of scanned documents in terms of
this is the information of the claims we
paid this claim under claim this
happened somewhere in the month of April
7th April and the past is going on but
we've already picked some on a
compliment because what happens in
during this one of time is in a lockdown
when your revenues are not coming and
your losses has happened it becomes a
double to each of our customers so we do
take care in terms of those things and
ensure that the claims process do not
stop even in the lockdown process
so in terms of for marine cargo or the
logistics lots of vehicles are stranded
on the road due to lock down what are
the provisions coverage in terms of
transit whether discovered or not I
thought I'll just do basics around that
so there are two types of storage
one is the incidental storage and the
other is the intentional storage I mean
let me give you some example of
incidental storage storage during during
your ordinary course of transit I mean
this incident of storage is covered in
your marine policy but intentional
storage is not covered in the marine
policy let me do an example say for
example this starting a transit from
Pune to Delhi and the consignment is
stored by the transport in the joy pool
without the knowledge of the customer
paper or transit of the change of driver
accident so this is the incident of
storage I mean your job I mean you're
transferring a good shuffle in Delhi and
in a job Jaipur you have instituted
storage this any loss between that it's
covered I mean when in that chapel is
also covered but think of another thing
a point for example in this situation if
the customer texts on tours of the goods
and stores in the Jaipur then the losses
happen then it's not covered because you
have taken alarm and boots in your
custody and the in the insurance is not
closed up at that point of time so if it
is incident with storage during the
transit you discover if it is
intentional change of storage it is not
covered in modern policy so there is
also certain class called the duration
clause in marine I mean basically the
marine policy ceases or the closes the
model to take delivery of the goods or
upon expiry of 60 days equal to the
Seawatch seven days if it is a railroad
voice or thirty days it's a bracket so
whichever covers first that on that
basis the marine policy ceases
so let me given situation once to two
examples on that suppose a transit
started on principle the March by Road
and reached the Calcutta on 15 April and
the consignment between Calcutta for
final unloading right in this case the
insurer needs to approach the insurance
company by producing the pill for
extends of the duration clause because
this is a railroad transit and for a
railroad transit it has to seven days of
four I mean duration of the transit
clause
see the reverse in terms of the
consonant is the jnp to both port in
Bombay and
10cc awaiting unloading there is a
automatic cover 60 days because if it is
a sea voyage it is 60 days so
considering the current situation only
dove extends from Pearson plus till 60
days beyond 60 days you know to get in
touch with your insurance company
he might charge you a little bit of
freedom and get the continue the
coverage so these are some of the
thoughts I thought I was share with you
because each one of us should be facing
some sort of probably around this and
giving you example would actually help
to clarify that I have already answered
the first one in terms of the the orange
one on the left side some of the
questions is because of delay is damaged
and it ends in charges covered
no it is not covered on the normal
marine policy if the question is
basically non delivery after arrival of
carrying vehicle at destination town due
to closure of the premises due to lock
them non-delivery resulting in damages
would be covered into the policy
extension of duration clause can be
checked with the underwriter either by
paying additional premium or by
modifications of deductibles both can be
done in discussing the insurance company
so these are some of the provisions
within the guidelines of marine nuisance
transit so they you know do aware of
this in terms of engineering the biggest
challenge basically is the cessation of
work I mean lot of Labour's are moved
out and the engineering guideline says
when I say engineering policy that
Mississippi two types of products that
is called erection always of the
contractors all lists so contact was
always a Michigan civil projects
erection always is basically on the
plant and missile development cooperates
of the large companies of the
development like transmission lines
those are basically it is and all these
products so that is exclusion of
coverage arising of cessation of walk
and this is basically related to
abundant Norwalk or posits because
people have left all the fuzzy related
for then your engineering posits policy
ceases in this case unit to intimate to
an insurance company and do all risk
management practices which is possible
to safeguard your risk please continue
to do that and keep your instance
company update about that I think that's
the thing you need to do some of the
questions is the extension of policy for
possible without p.m. no it is not if
you want to extend this policy because
in the last two three months because
there is for bid though no work has been
done and the project period will get
extended so when the project period get
extended you
we'll have to wait even for instance
company because insurance companies CAD
is the risk both in the abundant period
as well as the extension period so there
is a premium for that is there is a
premium rebate an extension to lock down
no such thing I mean things are not
allowed in terms of weight of that it
does the policy cover the expenses
towards mobilization of manpower and
recombinant of the full fledge
operations outside during lockdown
no such losses are covered can the
installments we have depth no not at all
the insurance can abuse so these are
some of the guidelines or thought
process in terms of what is covered in
the Indian products and what is not
covered and the the biggest thing is
basically in terms of cessation of walk
and there you need to keep your instance
company updated about that so that's the
thought around the engineering risk this
is one big thing around health insurance
to amend or of course the awareness of
insurance is increased a lot in terms of
health side because of this forbidden
things what has happened is during this
period government has issued a circular
specifically for all those corporates or
all those SMEs won't start their
operations they have to take a health
insurance policies for the workers who
want to start the operations this is a
copy of the Government of India circular
and in many of the corporates they have
not do not have a health insurance
policies sometimes they have a ESIC
covered basically the employer state
insurance cover
and what ESIC says his ESS basically
covers all those employees up to 10
employees are except the Chandigarh and
Mara steroids upper limit is 20
employees and you know this covers up to
10 employees up with salary of 21
thousand per month and it is mandated to
cover those under ES health insurance
and the same is also regularly checked
by the Labor Department on the same and
under the ESIC two health insurance the
treatment cannot happen outside yourself
that's the biggest restrictions because
you have to go only to ESS hospitals and
ESIC hospitals may not be equipped to
handle your health insurance cover and
if your company has taken a head
by excluding yes I say yeah it is it
takes care of this guidelines out there
but the normal questions that come is
sir I have a blue personal accident does
it cover this guidelines no it is not
your workmen compensation policy does
not cover this guideline you have to
have a ESS a cover or a group health
insurance cover either of them they will
do work and the advantage of having a
separate group health insurance company
group insurance cover is you can define
your limits you can define a cement
short what level of coverages you want
and the other question that comes is
does your health group health insurance
covers covertly mci it covers you for it
gives the normal corporate teams are
covered under yes I see all the local
insurance and lot of people are not even
aware of this so what has happened is
not many new products has come in the
market in terms of covert hours so there
is specific Ovid cover that the two
types of cover to cover three types of
who would cover one is individual
benefit cover in the market so if you
are detected with the probe it positive
by the government authorized
laboratories or things you get a fixed
cement around that that's all benefit
the cover of it there is a indemnity
cover of it which effectively means if
you are detected detected with for bid
or admitted in the hospital's you shall
get those bills and the insurance
company pay for that and the third is
the insurance companies have come up
with a group covert cover basically
covering your employees and workers in
terms of same company there are 30
employees there are 50 employees you can
take a group health insurance cover for
a forbidden so these are the broadly
three areas we just come up in terms of
food coverages out there lot of
innovations are happening out there in
terms of how do you help the customers
in terms of ensuring that the COBIT
expenses are covered out of that and
there are multiple products I believe in
the market I mean I say selamat has
launched a forward health in Dominica
Rico good health benefit cover and a
covert group covert cover for the
employees and some of the companies what
they've done also is since they do not
used to take health insurance earlier
neither they had a co bid covered they
have also taken a vanilla health
insurance basically is a cutter down
version of
pterence we're in the premium is little
a little bit lower compared to larger
production full-fledged group health
insurance and that covers Cove it as
well as the non covered expenses I mean
in terms of group health as they ottoman
covers so when it's a you say group
health insurance is basically it phases
phase you when you are hospitalized so
some of the corporates so have taken is
simple vanilla GTI cover the guqin
insurance cover which covers both
covered as well as non covered expenses
out there I think that's a very
intelligent move over by some of the
companies so they have done because
ultimately one needs to take care of the
employees and Cove it is going to stay
out here it is not going to overnight
it's clear out there so you need to
protect your employees out there so
that's the thought around group health
so this is one big risk which has
recently become much more activated in
the last year after covered happening so
what has happened is since majority of
the employees are working from home and
they're accessing informations from home
they are not under the safeguard of the
corporate safety or security from the
cyber point of view they are using their
wife at home or probably a modern model
committee at home and ethics so the and
they are dealing with lot of data of the
corporate so from their home so there is
a quite a surge in the cyber risk of
hacking other things happening they've
seen in the last two three months and
you to give you some of the examples
what has happened is the cyber criminals
are basically capitals in the public
view I mean there is a fear around that
and there is 667 person spike in Kiruna
wise little phishing scams I mean this
is a data which I a value in Google and
a lot many sites out there I mean
there's some 16,000 new domains
registered and around some to be genuine
unofficial most of them are formula
round covert scams out there so there
are cyber excursions in the name of
donations are damning lot of people are
using this more in terms of using doing
a cyber attack in terms of the
corporates or the employees out there
the threats now an awful lot basically
one is of course your data security
threats increased financial frauds which
is happening
there and in time this may continue
beyond post forward as well and some of
the industries which are most hardly
heat around this is basically your
healthcare or hospitality your ideas
companies your banking and financial
services company so these are big time
hit because of the cyber I mean normally
this SMEs do not use to take about cyber
risk not worry too much about cyber is
because they have much larger risk to
handle and ethics bigger is to handle so
but now the the recent past was in order
for this SMEs getting hit by this cyber
as well so just to give you something in
terms of what is this product which
covers this product basically covers
your financial losses that results in
the data breaches and other cyber events
this covers your notifications cost your
forensic cost your cyber extortion cost
and third party as a result of cyber
incidents so the currently I mean if you
see there are two types of products
available in the market you you can have
a group cyber cover for all your
employees as a company that is also a
retail cyber cover individual so can
take a cyber cover I mean hacking can
happen from a mobile itself can you
laptop itself I mean from your iPod at
iPad is full so you can also take a
retail cyber cover all of those products
are not just a value but we have
recently launched even a retail cyber
cover we have a group cyber cover for
the employees so either of them you can
check to protect your plan I mean risk
other
corporates from the cyber because this
is going to the dominant risk so these
are some of the broad thoughts I thought
I should must share with you in terms of
you know what are the risk which is
affecting all of us in this period and
I've already shared with this basically
engineering
property marine cyber and health is a
broad areas there beyond it this area is
also a multiple risk but primarily this
risk accounts for majority of the things
my suggestions to each one of you of
course would be risk I mean the SMEs at
this point of time has multiple risks
one of course from the business point of
view there is a lot of challenges out
there
god forbid I mean they also have a risk
from the insurance of the pond
the risk point of view are out there and
to take adequate coverages for your
plans for a machineries follow-up
employees for your assets and insurance
might cost you a little bit lesser of
the risk but don't forget to take
insurance I mean the biggest challenge
today in this country or in India is not
of SMEs are uninsured I mean normally
the belief that Perry will strike
somebody else not to me I mean that's a
belief they carry and we need to change
that perception in terms of as a aware
customer are aware insurance company we
need to handhold each other in terms of
helping each other in terms of getting
the discover even if there is challenges
around getting a full-fledged cover all
I will request each one of you is you
you can have a cut down cover as
Cottrell version of your cover I mean
you can always get in touch with the
insurance company saying I need a
reduced version of that because there is
issues and only few liquidity a walk in
capital you can also ask for instance
come liquor I mean cut alone cover and
you can there will be a Q&A session on
the live on the day it will be like
please do ask your questions our team
would be there to answer those queries
out there when it comes up and if you
still have any other queries you can do
put me a mail or to my colleague we wake
when you about a given is email ID for
any queries related to presentations so
little any inference for ease or any
queries a little risk to mail us I will
certainly help you do in terms of giving
you guidance in terms of how do you
cover this risk and how can we can help
you in terms of business as well so
thank you so much and please we'll be
happy to answer any of your questions
and thanks so much for your tax as well